let questions = [
    {
        numb: 1,
        question: "What is fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Study of fluid behaviour at rest and in motion",
        options: [
            "Study of fluid behaviour at rest",
            "Study of fluid behaviour in motion",
            "Study of fluid behaviour at rest and in motion",
            "Study of fluid behaviour at rest and at oscillation"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Which of the following is the basic principle of fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "All of the mentioned",
        options: [
            "Momentum principlet",
            "Energy equation",
            "Continuity equation",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 3,
        question: "What is fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Fluid mechanics enables to comprehend the behaviour of fluids under a variety of forces & atmospheric conditions",
        options: [
            "Fluid mechanics enables to comprehend the behaviour of solid fluids under pressure",
            "Fluid mechanics enables to comprehend the behaviour of fluids under a variety of forces & atmospheric conditions",
            "Fluid mechanics enables to comprehend the behaviour of fluids under various temperatures only",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 4,
        question: "If a person studies about a fluid which is at rest, what will you call his domain of study?",
        answer: "Fluid Statics",
        options: [
            "Fluid Dynamics",
            "Fluid Mechanics",
            "Fluid Statics",
            "Fluid Kinematics"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 5,
        question: "Which among the following is the standard symbol for Atwood number?",
        answer: "A",
        options: [
            "Ar",
            "A",
            "a",
            "AR"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 6,
        question: "Which of the following method is used exclusively in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Eulerian method",
        options: [
            "Eulerian method",
            "Lagrangian method",
            "Neither Lagrangian nor Eulerian method",
            "Both Lagrangian and Eulerian methods"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 7,
        question: " Which of the following method is most commonly used in fluid mechanics for analysis?",
        answer: "Eulerian method",
        options: [
            "Eulerian method",
            "Control volume analysis",
            "Langragian method",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 8,
        question: "Which of the following method is used exclusively in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Reynolds number is greater than 2000",
        options: [
            "High viscosity of fluid",
            "Reynolds number is greater than 2000",
            "Reynolds number is less than 2000",
            "The density of the fluid is low"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Which among the following is the standard symbol for Blake number?",
        answer: "Bl",
        options: [
            "ba",
            "b",
            "Bi",
            "Bl"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Which of the following method is used exclusively in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "zero",
        options: [
            "unity",
            "constant",
            "infinite",
            "zero"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 11,
        question: "Which among the following is the standard symbol for Archimedes number?",
        answer: "Eulerian method",
        options: [
            "Ar",
            "A",
            "a",
            "AR"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 12,
        question: "Which among the following is referred to as the temperature at a stagnation point in the flow of fluids in fluid mechanics and thermodynamics.",
        answer: "Stagnation temperature",
        options: [
            "Absolute temperature",
            "Maximum temperature",
            "Stagnation temperature",
            "Hydraulic temperature"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 13,
        question: "What is model testing?",
        answer: "Performance testing",
        options: [
            "Overall testing",
            "Function testing",
            "Partial testing",
            "Performance testing"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 14,
        question: "Which of the following method is used exclusively in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Reynolds number is less than 2000",
        options: [
            "Low viscosity",
            "The density of the fluid is high",
            "Reynolds number is greater than 2000",
            "Reynolds number is less than 2000"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 15,
        question: "Which among the following provides the third principle in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Conservation of linear momentum",
        options: [
            "Conservation of Heat",
            "Conservation of volume",
            "Conservation of linear momentum",
            "Conservation of mass"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 16,
        question: "When a fluid is subjected to resistance, it undergoes a volumetric change due to __________",
        answer: "Compressibility",
        options: [
            "Cohesion",
            "Strain",
            "Compressibility",
            "Adhesion"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 17,
        question: "The compressible flow is assumed to be _____________",
        answer: "Isentropic only",
        options: [
            "Eulerian method",
            "Isentropic only",
            "Isentropic and adiabatic",
            "Polytropic"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 18,
        question: "Which of the following method is used exclusively in fluid mechanics?",
        answer: "Work",
        options: [
            "Velocity",
            "Accelerating mass",
            "Volume",
            "Work"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Open channel flow takes place _______",
        answer: "On a free surface",
        options: [
            "In a pump",
            "Within a cylindrical depth",
            "On a free surface",
            "In the pipe"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Which of the following is a type of fluid based on viscosity?",
        answer: "Eulerian method",
        options: [
            "Real Fluid",
            "Ideal Fluid",
            "Newtonian Fluid",
            "All of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 21,
        question: "The viscous force the relative motion between the adjacent layers of a fluid in motion. Which of the following flowing fits best in the sentence?",
        answer: "opposes",
        options: [
            "never affects",
            "may effect under certain conditions",
            "facilitates",
            "opposes"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 22,
        question: "Pressure intensity or force due to pressure gradient for fluid at rest is considered as which of the following kind of force?",
        answer: "Surface force",
        options: [
            "Body force",
            "Force due to motion",
            "Surface force",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 23,
        question: "Pressure variation for compressible fluid is maximum for which of the following kind of process?",
        answer: "Isothermal",
        options: [
            "Adiabatic",
            "Quasi Static",
            "Isothermal",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 24,
        question: "Which of the following principle is used for calculating the centre of pressure?",
        answer: "Performance testing",
        options: [
            "Principle of balancing of momentum",
            "Principle of momentum",
            "Principle of conservation of energy",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 25,
        question: "Which of the following cannot be the value of absolute pressure of a fluid at any point?",
        answer: " – 1 bar",
        options: [
            "0",
            "1.45 bar",
            "– 1 bar",
            "24 bar"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 26,
        question: "When the body is completely or partially immersed in a fluid, how much its weight be distributed for it to be in stable equilibrium.",
        answer: "Around the lower part",
        options: [
            "Is independent of weight distribution",
            "Around the lower part",
            "Around the upper part",
            "None of the mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 27,
        question: "Which of the following equation must be perfunctorily satisfied while dealing with fluid flow problems?",
        answer: "Continuity equation",
        options: [
            "Newton’s third law",
            "Law of conservation of momentum",
            "Continuity equation",
            "Newton’s second law"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 28,
        question: "Which of the following equation must be perfunctorily satisfied while dealing with fluid flow problems?",
        answer: "Continuity equation",
        options: [
            "Newton’s third law",
            "Law of conservation of momentum",
            "Continuity equation",
            "Newton’s second law"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 29,
        question: "Which among the following is an assumption of Hagen-Poiseuille equation?",
        answer: "Fluid is laminar",
        options: [
            "Fluid is uniform",
            "Fluid is laminar",
            "Fluid is turbulent",
            "Fluid is compressible"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 30,
        question: "Which of the following is a formula for the friction factor of circular pipes?",
        answer: "64/Re",
        options: [
            "Re/64",
            "16/Re",
            "64/Re",
            "Re/16"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 31,
        question: "Which among the following is not global parameters of fluid?",
        answer: "External diameter",
        options: [
            "Mass flow rate",
            "Density",
            "Viscosity",
            "External diameter"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 32,
        question: "Which of the following is the mathematical technique used to predict physical parameters?",
        answer: "Dimensional analysis",
        options: [
            "Dimensional analysis",
            "Temperature analysis",
            "Pressure analysis",
            "Combustion analysis"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 33,
        question: "Which among the following have the same forces acting on them?",
        answer: "Dynamic similarity",
        options: [
            "Dynamic similarity",
            "Geometric similarity",
            "Conditional similarity",
            "Kinematic similarity"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 34,
        question: "Which one of the following is a major loss?",
        answer: "frictional loss",
        options: [
            "frictional loss",
            "shock loss",
            "entry loss",
            "exit loss"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 35,
        question: "Which property of the fluid accounts for the major losses in pipes?",
        answer: "viscosity",
        options: [
            "density",
            "specific gravity",
            "viscosity",
            "compressibility"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 36,
        question: "The frictional resistance for fluids in motion is",
        answer: "proportional to the velocity in laminar flow and to the square of the velocity in turbulent flow",
        options: [
            "proportional to the velocity in laminar flow and to the square of the velocity in turbulent flow",
            "proportional to the square of the velocity in laminar flow and to the velocity in turbulent flow",
            "proportional to the velocity in both laminar flow and turbulent flow",
            "proportional to the square of the velocity in both laminar flow and turbulent flow"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 37,
        question: "The frictional resistance for fluids in motion is",
        answer: "proportional to the surface area of contact",
        options: [
            "inversely proportional to the square of the surface area of contact",
            "inversely proportional to the surface area of contact",
            "proportional to the square of the surface area of contact",
            "proportional to the surface area of contact"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 38,
        question: "A liquid flows through pipes 1 and 2 with the same flow velocity. If the ratio of their pipe diameters d1 : d2 be 3:2, what will be the ratio of the head loss in the two pipes?",
        answer: "2:3",
        options: [
            "3:2",
            "9:4",
            "2:3",
            "4:9"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 39,
        question: "A liquid flowss through two similar pipes 1 and 2. If the ratio of their flow velocities v1 : v2 be 2:3, what will be the ratio of the head loss in the two pipes?",
        answer: "4:9",
        options: [
            "3:2",
            "9:4",
            "2:3",
            "4:9"
        ]
    },
    {
        numb: 40,
        question: "What is model testing?",
        answer: "half",
        options: [
            "equal to",
            "half",
            "twice",
            "four times"
        ]
    },
]
